残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で
運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて到達
もっと走る熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
次回予告
Oh, come on, Kaji.
This is what all the girls are wearing.
Oh, really?
Uh-huh.
Oh, I'm so anxious about this school trip.
I just know we'll have a great time.
So, where is your class going?
Okinawa!
It's gonna be awesome.
We're even gonna go scuba diving.
Scuba diving, huh?
Boy, it's been years since the last time I went diving.
Hey, where'd you go for your school trip, Kaji?
Well, actually, we didn't have one.
Why is that?
Just a little thing called the second impact.
What?
Did you just think I can't go on the trip?
Yep.
Well, why not?
It's part of your job.
You mean I'm on permanent standby?
You got it.
What idiot decided that?
This one, the operations planning manager.
Hmph.
Shinji, why don't you stop hiding behind that cup of tea and talk some sense into this woman?
Act like a man!
Well, you know, actually, I had kind of expected that we wouldn't be allowed to go.
So, you've already given up.
Mm-hmm.
Huh, pathetic.
There's nothing more useless than a housebroken male.
Hey, don't talk about me like that.
Look!
Hm?
I know how you must feel, but there's just no other way.
There's always the possibility that an angel might attack while you're away.
So I get stuck here on standby status while everyone else is having fun?
Why is it that we're the ones who always have to be ready to defend against them?
Any good officer knows that the best defense is a good offense.
Why can't we find them and attack them first?
If we could do that, we would do it.
Look, think of this as an opportunity to get ahead for a change.
The two of you can catch up on your studies while the rest of your classmates are on the trip.
Or did you think I hadn't seen these report cards?
I guess you thought I wouldn't know about your test scores yet.
Well, all of your grades are forwarded directly to my terminal,
and I have been very disappointed with the both of you.
Ha, this is so silly, and this school's grades are just dumb.
The old-fashioned numeric grading scale you use on your exams is stupid.
In Rome, do as the Romans do.
You could at least try to adjust to Japanese school life.
This sucks!
Hey, Asuka, I'll bring you back something nice!
Ha, ha! Sayonara, suckers!
Hey, don't worry. I'll have enough fun for the both of you!
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Post the survey data on Mount Asuma from Balthazar to Melchior as soon as possible.
A school trip, huh? That sounds pretty reckless in times like these.
I guess the idea is to let all the kids have time to get out and act like kids while they can.
Hmm, what have you got there, Shinji?
Basic physics primer.
Oh, you're such an obedient student.
Well, I'll have to study it anyway. I mean, I...
Well, if I can't go diving in Okinawa, let's do it here.
Do what?
Diving, of course.
So what are you working on?
Let's see.
You can't solve an easy problem like this?
There, all done.
It's easy when you know how.
How can you solve a difficult problem like this and not make good grades on your tests?
It's because I'm having too much trouble figuring out what the questions are.
You mean you can't read the questions in Japanese?
That's right. I still haven't learned all of the kanji yet.
I didn't have to study it in college.
You went to college?
Yeah. I graduated last year.
So, what does this one say?
It's a question about thermal expansion.
Thermal expansion? Oh, man, that's kid stuff.
To put it in terms you'll understand, most things expand when they get hot and contract when they get cold.
Well, it sounds simple enough.
Look, if I were to warm up my breasts with my hands, do you think they'd grow bigger or smaller?
I don't know. I don't think about things like that.
Such a boring little boy.
Hey, Shinji! Looky, looky!
Back-rolling, Three!
Oh...
This just isn't clear enough.
But the report from the Mount Asuma Earthquake Research Lab implies we should take a closer look at this shadow.
We can't ignore it.
What do the Magi say?
It's 50-50 odds.
Who's up there?
Captain Katsuragi has already arrived at the site.
You're going, 2G.
Pin the probe down another 500.
Depth 1,200.
The pressure-resistant partition is cracking.
Katsuragi.
If it breaks, we'll pay for the damage.
200 more, please.
We're monitoring a reaction.
Start analysis.
Right.
The probe is imploded due to the extreme pressure.
Did you get it?
Just barely.
The pattern is blue.
Then there's no doubt.
It's an angel.
This laboratory is now under the jurisdiction of NERV.
There will be no unauthorized phone calls.
Any access to the outside world is prohibited, and all records pertaining to these events will be classified top secret.
Katsuragi here.
I need an A-17 from Commander Ikari.
Top priority.
Watch what you're saying, Captain.
This isn't a secure line.
I know that.
Switch me to a scramble line immediately.
At A-17, you want to make an offensive attack?
That is correct.
No.
It's too dangerous.
Have you forgotten what happened 15 years ago?
No, but consider this.
This is our chance to move from a state of perpetual defense to an offensive posture.
The risk would be enormous.
However, I'm sure that you must be aware of how important it is to obtain a living angel as a sample, am I correct?
We will not tolerate failure.
Failure.
If we fail, it will result in the extinction of the entire human race.
Are you really going to do it, Commander?
Is that an angel?
Yes.
It's some sort of chrysalis form that precedes the adult stage we're familiar with.
This operation's prime objective will be to capture this angel.
We must capture it alive and in a form as close to its original state as possible.
And if we fail?
Then you must destroy it immediately.
Understood?
Roger!
The designated pilot will be...
Oh, pick me, please!
I love to go diving!
It's going to be me, as always.
Asuka.
Huh?
You will carry out the mission.
Sure!
It's gonna be easy!
And me?
The special equipment we'll be using hasn't been standardized for use in the prototype.
Ray and Unit Zero will remain here on standby.
I see.
Oh, poor little Ray.
She doesn't get to have any fun!
Now that an A-17 has been ordered, we've got to roll out immediately.
Get ready.
Roger!
Huh?
You know, this heat-resistant entry-plug suit doesn't seem any different from our regular ones.
Press the switch on your right wrist.
Okay!
Oh!
What?
They brought the nails!
Unit 2 should be ready now.
No!
No way!
How could you?
This exosuit is designed to protect you.
Type D equipment is for combat under extreme environmental duress, not high fashion.
That my Unit 2?
The poor thing!
Forget it!
I won't do it!
I'm not appearing in public in this stupid thing!
This is the sort of thing you have Shinji for!
I'm so disappointed!
I was looking forward to seeing you in action!
He's there behind Opa-loopa!
Dr. Akagi, I just can't let Paji see me in this awful-looking thing!
Are we having problems down there?
Sort of, yes.
Excuse me, but I could...
I will go in Unit 2.
Ah!
Oh, no, you don't!
The only way you're using my Unit 2 is over my dead body!
I'd rather do it than let her take my place!
I'm sorry, Liebkin.
They made me do it!
Ava Units 1 and 2 have arrived.
Have both units stand by.
Reposition the laser bore and stand ready on the crane.
Roger.
Hey, is Kaji here yet?
God's gift won't be coming.
He's got no business here.
No, but I wanted him to see me in my greatest triumph to date!
An A-17 has been ordered.
This will include a freeze of all assets.
So that means that some people will be in trouble.
Why didn't you try to stop them?
I had no way of stopping this.
This order was an official one, you know.
But you must know that if Nerv fails at this,
the entire world will perish.
Don't worry.
Not even they are that arrogant.
What are those jets?
The UN and the Air Force will be standing by.
Until this mission's over anyway.
Are they here to help us?
No, they're here to clean up the mess.
Just in case we fail.
Uh, what do you mean?
They'll use N2 depth charges to destroy the Angel.
And us as well.
This job sucks!
What kind of a jerk would order something like that?
Commander Ikari.
Huh?
Laser operation complete.
The board path has been secured.
The Type-D equipment is functioning normally.
Unit 2 is ready and in position.
Understood.
Asuka, are you ready?
Ready when you are.
Let's do it!
Unit 2 is entering the lava.
Hey, look at this, Chi-Chi!
A perfect dinner sign!
Current depth, 170.
Rate of descent, 20.
No problems detected.
Visibility is zero.
I can't see a thing.
Switching to CT monitor.
Even with this, I can barely see a thing.
Depth is 400.
450, 500, 550, 600, 650.
900, 950, 1000, 1050.
We're over the maximum safety depth.
Depth is 1300.
Unit has reached estimated target level.
Asuka, what do you see?
I'm not detecting anything!
It's not here!
The lava currents must be faster than we thought.
The target's velocity certainly doesn't match our predictions.
Hurry up and recalculate.
Descend further.
Continue the operation.
Huh?
Depth is 1350.
1400.
A crack has occurred on the second coolant pipe.
Depth is 1480.
We have exceeded the maximum allowed depth.
But we haven't made contact with the target yet.
Keep going.
How's it going, Asuka?
Nice and toasty.
I just want to finish this and take a shower.
There's a nice hot spring near here.
We'll go there once this is over.
Just hang in there a little longer.
Maximum allowed depth plus 120.
Ava Unit 2 has lost its progressive knife.
Maximum allowed depth plus 200.
Captain Katsuragi, you've got to stop this.
Have you forgotten that there's a human being in there?
I will manage this operation as I see fit.
Continue to descend.
I agree with Misato.
I am okay.
I can go on.
Depth 1780.
Unit has reached the corrected target depth.
Wait.
I see it.
The target is in sight.
Prepare for capture.
All right.
Because of the convection current that's moving both you and the target,
you'll have just one chance to make contact.
I understand.
Just leave it to me.
30 meters to contact.
Relative velocity 2.2 on the axis.
The electromagnetic cage has been spread.
No problems detected.
The target has been captured.
Nice work, Asuka.
The operation is completed.
I'm beginning my ascent.
Asuka, are you all right?
Well, of course I am.
The only thing we have to fear is fear itself.
This was easy.
Man, this isn't an entry plug suit.
It's a sauna bath.
Oh, I just want to go and take a cold shower.
Sounds like the tension let loose all at once.
Yeah.
Were you scared about this operation?
I sure was.
Well, yeah.
If something had gone wrong, it could have been another...
I know.
Second impact.
All over again.
It's going crazy!
Oh, no!
It started to hatch.
It's earlier than we predicted.
Cage status.
There's no way it can handle this.
Abort the capture.
Jettison the cage.
Damn!
We're changing the operation.
We've got to destroy that angel.
Unit 2, prepare for combat.
Do it, Asuka.
You got it.
Damn it!
I forgot that I dropped the prognite!
The angel!
Releasing holster!
It's fast!
This is no good!
I'm lost it again!
And if this lousy visibility wasn't bad enough, I'm also too hot and this disgusting soup stuck
to my body with sweat!
This really sucks!
Asuka!
We're going to drop you Unit 1's progressive knife.
Stand ready!
Understood!
Huh?
Oh, jeez!
Drop it now, Shinji!
Here he comes!
Forty seconds to knife arrival.
The angel is approaching rapidly.
Fuck off!
Go away!
Hurry up with that thing!
No!
Fall faster!
Whoa!
What the hell?
What do you think that thing's built out of?
Left leg damaged!
D-Q-phylator!
Die, damn you!
Oh!
Oh, my God!
The extreme heat has distended that thing's molecular structure!
The prog knife won't work against it!
What?
Then what do we do?
Think physics!
Thermal expansion!
Yeah!
Of course!
The coolant!
Transfer all of the internal coolant pressure to cable number three!
Do it!
Ah!
I'm done it but...
That's it.
I'm done for.
Shinji!
Idiot.
You show off.
Hello, are the people from Nerve here somewhere?
Yeah, we're here.
I need your signature here.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
It's from Kaji.
What is this?
The springs are over that way.
Ah, this feels like heaven.
Oh, boy.
I never thought a bath could feel this good.
Shinji, can you hear me?
Yes, ma'am.
Would you be a deer and throw me the body shampoo?
We ran out of hours.
Sure.
Here it comes.
Roger.
Ow!
You idiot!
Watch where you're throwing you dark!
Oh, t-sorry.
He hid me in my most private part.
Oh, let me take a look.
Oh, watch your fingers!
Wow, your skin is so soft and smooth.
Put this down.
You're tickling me.
How do you like this?
Oh, don't touch me there!
Oh, come on, hot gist.
Ah!
Thermal expansion.
How embarrassing.
Huh?
Oh, the scar.
It's something that happened during the second impact.
You know my past.
About everything, don't you?
Well, it's part of my job.
It's all ancient history now.
We really are a new world of life.
I don't know what kind of evolution is.
You know my past. About everything, don't you?
Well, it's part of my job. It's all ancient history now. We really ought to let it go.
It's like a Jupiter at night. Bring another world. Hold my hand.
Bring another world. Darling, kiss me. Fill my heart with soul. And let this sing forever more.
You are all alone. For all I want, sleep on the door.
Another world. Please be true.
Another world. I love you.
I love you.